Office of the Dean, Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Records UA135
Tufts Archival Research Center
Office of the Dean, Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Records
1963 -- 2018
Tufts Archival Research Center
Graduate School of Arts and Sciences
Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences for Research
UA135
31.65 Linear Feet 30 boxes
2 Digital Object(s)
This collection contains records created by the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences regarding the Graduate Institute for Teaching, the Summer Institute, graduate research awards, Teaching Assistant orientation,and various ceremonies. Materials include photographs, memos and correspondence, publications, self-assessment and accreditation documentation, reports, and financial records.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series: Additional accessions; and 2020 accessions.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact TARC for further details.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records created by the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences about the Graduate Institute for Teaching, the Summer Institute, graduate research awards, Teaching Assistant orientation, award ceremonies, hooding ceremonies, various programs, and polices. These records include photographs, memos, correspondence, publications, brochures, self-assessments, accreditation documentation, annual reports, strategic plans, proposals for new degree programs, graduate degree statistics, financial documents, award applications and nominees paperwork, and continuous learning materials for department staff, as well as general office files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 2010-2020, accessions 2010.022, 2014.003, 2014.008, 2014.012, 2014.077, and UA-2021-017.
Administration and Governance -- Planning, evaluation, policies & procedures; Curriculum and Instruction -- Scholarships, Fellowships, Awards; Research and Research Administration
- Additional accessions, 1982 -- 2012; UA135.001
  - Subject Files, 1985 -- 2003; UA135-001 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Dean's planner, subject files, 1985 -- 2003; UA135-002 (Box 2)
  - FRAC meetings, 1999 -- 2005; UA135-003 (Box 3)
  - Policies and Program files, 1982 -- 2003; UA135-004 (Box 4)
  - Hooding ceremony; subject files, 1995 -- 2007; UA135-005 (Box 5)
  - Department files, 1991 -- 2003; UA135-006 (Box 6)
  - Subject files, 1991 -- 2003; UA135-007 (Box 7)
  - Subject files and commencement, 1993 -- 2000; UA135-008 (Box 8)
  - Summer institute and Kanarek files, 1999 -- 2005; UA135-009 (Box 9)
  - Award files and UEP files, 1999 -- 2005; UA135-010 (Box 10)
  - UEP and BSOT, 1991 -- 2001; UA135-011 (Box 11)
  - Brochures, posters, applications, handbooks, 1983 -- 2006; UA135-012 (Box 12)
  - Hooding program materials and photographs, 2003 -- 2011; UA135-013 (Box 13)
  - Hooding program digital photographs, 2003 -- 2011; UA135-014
  - GSAS and E Awards and Graduate Research Awards, 2007 -- 2011; UA135-015 (Box 14)
  - Graduate research awards, matriculation and TA orientation, 2002 -- 2011; UA135-016 (Box 15)
  - Awards ceremony photographs, 2000 -- 2010; UA135-017 (Box 16)
  - Awards ceremonies digital photographs, 2000 -- 2010; UA135-018
  - Graduate Institute for Teaching (GIFT) records (1 of 2), 2005 -- 2011; UA135-019; Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Scienc (Box 17)
  - Graduate Institute for Teaching (GIFT) records (2 of 2), 2005 -- 2011; UA135-020; Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Scienc (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Graduate School documents to archive (1 of 2), 2002 -- 2012; UA135-021; Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Scienc (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Graduate School documents to archive (2 of 2), 2002 -- 2012; UA135-022; Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Scienc (Box 20)
- 2020 accessions, 1963 -- 2018; UA135.000025; 10 Linear Feet 10 record cartons
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact TARC for further details.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by the Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 2020, accession UA-2021-017.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains office, course, curriculum development, and event files, as well as publications, annual reports, faculty meeting minutes, and Interdiciplinary Doctorate records (IDOC). Thes records were produced by the Office of the Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences at Tufts, and the bulk of the materials date from 1980-2018.
  - Office files, 1982 -- 2014; UA135.000026; 1 Linear Feet (Box 21)
    75 years from date of creation.
  - Office files, 1979 -- 2015; UA135.000027; 1 Linear Feet (Box 22)
  - Office and course files, 1995 -- 2015; UA135.000028; 1 Linear Feet (Box 23)
  - Office and course files, 1976 -- 2016; UA135.000029; 1 Linear Feet (Box 24)
    - GSAS awards ceremony, 2013; UA135.000036; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 DVD (Box Shared Digital Media 1)
  - Graduate lists, bulletins, and publications, 1963 -- 2008; UA135.000030; 1 Linear Feet (Box 25)
  - Publications and event files, 2005 -- 2013; UA135.000031; 1 Linear Feet (Box 26)
  - Course files, 1990 -- 1999; UA135.000032; 1 Linear Feet (Box 27)
  - Executive Committee files, degree lists, annual reports, and event files, 1982 -- 2018; UA135.000033; 1 Linear Feet (Box 28)
    - Photo contest, Anna Murray, 2013; UA135.000037; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 CD (Box Shared Digital Media 1)
  - Departmental annual reports, faculty meeting minutes, Interdisciplinary Doctorate (IDOC) and course development files, 1987 -- 2012; UA135.000034; 1 Linear Feet (Box 29)
  - Departmental annual reports, faculty meeting minutes, Interdisciplinary Doctorate (IDOC) files, and curriculum development and course files, 1987 -- 2016; UA135.000035; 1 Linear Feet (Box 30)